

#### CONTACT



Bilbao, Spain



hello@xmartinez.dev



xmartinez.dev



@xmartinez

#### LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

Basque

# **XABIER MARTINEZ**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I'm Xabi, a software engineer specialising in the backend with devops mindset, mainly working in the Go programming language. But I don't discard the opportunity to work with other technologies. Big fan of KISS principle and don't reinventing the well.

I'm currently working at Arex Markets as Platform Engineer, building shared services, taking care of the infrastructure, improving developer experience and helping other developers.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Platform engineer

Arex Markets | Jul 2021 - Present

- Simplify kubernetes and AWS infrastructure moving to IaC.
- Improved CI/CD pipelines, moving from Jenkins to GH actions.
- Standardize deployment setups, defining widely use pipeline charts, and a base helm chart for services setup.
- Help other developers in the day by day.
- Develop transversal libraries and services in Go such as AuthN/AuthZ.

Go | Node.is | PostgreSQL | K8S | AWS | GPC | Helm | Terraform

### **Backend Developer**

Paack | Jul 2020 - Jul 2021

- Worked on different backend services in Go, exposing graphql API for frontend.
- Internal service communication via gRPC and asynchronously using Pub/Sub.
- Integrating with third parties such as Twillio, Google and auth0.
- CI/CD using GitHub actions and deploying to kubernetes.

Go | GCP | GraphQL | PostgreSQL | RabbitMQ

## Software Developer

Arex Markets | Nov 2018 - Jul 2020

- Involved in the definition and implementation of a service (front and back-end) to handle onboarding of the new customers, with different flows and external integrations.
- Worked on developments around financial data, such as, invoice importing from third parties or financial transactions management.
- Setup deployments, pubsub queues, and other infrastructure stuff.

Go | Node.js | TypeScript | Vue.js | PostgreSQL | Docker | AWS | GPC

## Backend Developer

Holaluz | Feb 2018 - Nov 2018

- Created from scratch a new managing tool for sales team.
- Build a service to handle automatically rejections from distributors when a customer wants to join.
- Move legacy code to a new service cleaning the code and adding tests, also fix many bugs on legacy code.
- Insfraestructure tasks, such as, create an ansible script to automatize the deployment of Nuxt static apps to Amazon S3.

PHP | Symfony | Laravel | Vue.js | Angular | PostgreSQL | MySQL | AWS

#### Software Developer

Inbenta | Feb 2016 - Feb 2018

## Squad Leader

Jun 2017 - Feb 2018

• Involved in the development of a massive content importer from different sources, such as, Web (crawling), REST APIs, Zendesk, Salesforce, Shopify, Discourse... to automatically import contents to the company platform, allowing the client configure it selfs.

#### Project Manager & Developer

Feb 2016 - May 2017

- Managed projects related to chat-bots, NLP search and ticketing. Talking with clients to analyse the needs and viability
- Developed functionalities for customer adapting company product to each them.

PHP | Vue.js | jQuery | MySQL

# Developer Intern

Arin Innovation | Oct 2014 - Feb 2016

- I did my first internship at Arin Innovation, a consulting services company.
- My daily work was to talk with clients to get the requirements and develop them. There
  I learned to apply the knowledge learned to develop with Oracles tools, such as JD
  Edwards and Oracle DB.
- First I was contracted for one year, when it finished they proposed me to extend the contract.

Oracle | Oracle JD Edwards | Oracle DB | PS/SQL | Oracle BI publisher

## **EDUCATION**

# **Computer Science Engineering**

University of the Basque Country | Sep 2011 - Jul 2015